Welcome back to the JupyterLab on Gradio day, so you'll remember where we left off.
グラジオのJupyterLabにようこそ｡
We'd written two user interfaces, one of them for chatting with GPT four using the function uh, stream
ひとつはGPTとチャットするためのもので､ GPTのストリーム機能を使ったもの｡
Uh, and so now I put it to you.
ええと､ それで今､ 君に聞いてみたんだ｡
Supposing we wrote a function like this.
仮にこのような関数を書いたとしよう｡
This function is like a composite function.
この関数は複合関数のようなものだ｡
It's a function that calls others in that it's called stream model.
ストリームモデルと呼ばれる､ 他を呼び出す関数だ｡
And it takes a prompt and it takes a model and it says if the model is GPT, then it calls stream GPT.
そして､ プロンプトを受け取り､ モデルを受け取り､ モデルがGPTであれば､ ストリームGPTを呼び出す｡
If the model is Claude, it calls stream.
モデルがクロードの場合､ ストリームを呼び出す｡
Claude otherwise throws an error.
そうでなければクロードはエラーを投げる｡
So it needs to be GPT or Claude.
だからGPTかクロードである必要がある｡
And then it basically iterates through and yields each chunk in turn.
そして､ 基本的に反復して各チャンクを順番に降ろす｡
So this is in fact I called it a function, but it's not.
だから､ 私はこれを関数と呼んだが､ 実はそうではないのだ｡
It's a generator.
発電機だ｡
Um, and it yields each chunk from one or the other models depending on which model is called.
そして､ どちらのモデルが呼び出されたかに応じて､ どちらか一方のモデルからチャンクを生成する｡
Well, obviously that's going to work fine.
まあ､ 明らかにうまくいくだろうね｡
That's now a function which has a few more variables.
これで､ さらにいくつかの変数を持つ関数になった｡
So as far as Gradio is concerned, that's just another function.
だから､ グラディオに関する限り､ それは単なる機能の一つに過ぎない｡
And that means that we can build a user interface very easily around that function.
つまり､ その機能を中心にユーザー・インターフェースを簡単に構築できるということだ｡
Let's look at it.
見てみよう｡
Here it is.
これだ｡
Here's an interface.
これがインターフェイスだ｡
The function it's taking is just this this sort of hybrid generator that we just written the inputs.
この関数が受け取るのは､ 今入力を書いたハイブリッドジェネレーターのようなものだ｡
Of course we're now going to have two inputs.
もちろん､ これで2つのインプットを持つことになる｡
One of them is going to be your message.
そのうちのひとつがあなたのメッセージになる｡
And the other of them I wish it were this easy.
そしてもうひとつは､ こんなに簡単だったらいいのにと思う｡
Drop down with two values GPT or Claude label select model.
GPTまたはClaudeラベルの2つの値のドロップダウンでモデルを選択します｡
And then, you know, have that as the output.
そして､ それを出力するんだ｡
Things are rarely that easy though.
しかし､ 物事がそんなに簡単であることはめったにない｡
Oh, but this is gradio, so things really are that easy.
ああ､ でもここはグラディオだから､ 物事は本当に簡単なんだ｡
Uh, sorry, I have to run this first.
申し訳ないが､ まずこれを実行しなければならない｡
There we go.
これでよし｡
It's not that easy.
そんなに簡単なことじゃない｡
You still do have to execute all of your code.
それでも､ すべてのコードを実行しなければならない｡
Uh, so here we go.
ええと､ それではどうぞ｡
We bring it up, we say something like, how do I get from times Square to Grand Central?
タイムズ・スクエアからグランド・セントラルまでどうやって行けばいいんだ？
and we pick one of our models.
そして､ 私たちのモデルの一つを選ぶ｡
Let's pick GPT and we submit that and they're streaming back in markdown.
GPTを選び､ それを送信すると､ マークダウンでストリーミングバックされる｡
Is GPT response to that question of directions.
その質問に対するGPTの回答が方向性だ｡
Enjoy your visit again at the end.
最後にもう一度､ 訪問を楽しもう｡
Very nice.
とても素晴らしい｡
Uh, I feel like it's giving more options this time, but there we go.
あー､ 今回は選択肢が増えたような気がするけど､ まあいいや｡
Maybe not.
そうではないかもしれない｡
You'll probably remember.
おそらく覚えているだろう｡
Uh, I can then just flip to Claude and ask Claude the same question.
クロードに同じ質問をすればいい｡
And here is Claude's answer to the same question.
同じ質問に対するクロードの答えはこうだ｡
Uh, using Claude haiku.
クロードの俳句を使ってね｡
That might explain why we're getting slightly shorter, more terse answers.
そのためか､ 回答はやや短く､ 簡潔なものになっている｡
But, uh, isn't that amazing?
でも､ それってすごいことじゃない？
Isn't that cool?
クールだろ？
We just built this functionality.
我々はこの機能を構築したばかりだ｡
We can flip between two different models, ask the same question, get the responses.
私たちは2つの異なるモデルの間を行き来し､ 同じ質問をして回答を得ることができる｡
Uh, you could just have this running sometime if you wanted a nice chat UI of your own and be able
もしチャットUIを作りたいなら､ このチャットUIをいつか実行させればいい｡
Uh, it's a useful little tool.
便利な道具だよ｡
Um, and, uh, yeah, you can imagine an obvious exercise that I'll leave for you is to simply add
うーん､ それで､ そうだな､ 双子座を単純にミックスに加えるという明らかな練習を想像できるだろう｡
Why not?
なぜだ？
You can imagine.
想像がつくだろう｡
It's super easy.
超簡単だよ｡
You just add in.
ただ加えるだけだ｡
Gemini is another option.
双子座という選択肢もある｡
I haven't shown you how to stream back from Gemini, but it's very similar and you can quickly google
Geminiからのストリーミングバックのやり方はまだお見せしていませんが､ とてもよく似ていますし､
it to see the documentation is very clear and then add it into the mix, and then push that code so
ググればドキュメントがとてもわかりやすいのですぐにわかります｡
That would be good.
それはいいことだ｡
All right.
分かった｡
So the next last for this lab is going to be okay.
だから､ このラボの次のラストは大丈夫だ｡
Let's take the company brochure generator we made last time and put a user interface around that.
前回作った会社案内ジェネレーターを使って､ ユーザー・インターフェースを作ってみよう｡
Wouldn't that be awesome.
すごいことだと思わない？
Uh, so now that you know, as I say, it's going to be really, really simple.
ええと､ だから､ 今言ったように､ 本当に､ 本当に簡単なことなんだ｡
So I've decided I'm going with the earlier version of the brochure.
だから､ 私は以前のバージョンのパンフレットを使うことに決めたんだ｡
We're just going to use a, we're going to use just the landing page only.
ランディング・ページだけを使います｡
We're not going to do the, the two step process where we collect all the links, because that's maybe
すべてのリンクを集めるという2段階のプロセスを行うつもりはない｡
Um, we're just going to have a simpler version of the website class that has URL, title and text,
ええと､ URL､ タイトル､ テキストを持つウェブサイト・クラスのシンプルなバージョンを用意するだけです｡
We use the requests package, and we use the wonderful Beautifulsoup to parse to strip out things we
リクエスト・パッケージを使い､ 素晴らしいビューティフル・スープを使って解析し､ どうでもいいものを取り除いてテキストを取得する｡
And there is a little getcontext helper to give us sort of getcontents helper to give us the page title
そして､ 小さなgetcontextヘルパーがあり､ getcontentsヘルパーのようなもので､ ページのタイトルと本文を与えてくれる｡
So that's our helper class.
これがヘルパークラスだ｡
Remember to run it.
忘れずに実行すること｡
System prompt.
システムプロンプト｡
You're in a system that analyzes the contents of a company website landing page and creates a short
あなたは､ 企業のウェブサイトのランディングページの内容を分析し､ 短いパンフレットを作成するシステムに入っている｡
In markdown there is a system prompt.
マークダウンにはシステム・プロンプトがある｡
So here is a stream brochure function that takes a company name, a URL and a model.
ここでは､ 会社名､ URL､ モデルを受け取るパンフレットのストリーム機能を紹介します｡
Uh, and it's going to say please generate a company brochure for company name.
会社名のパンフレットを作成してください｡
Here is their landing page.
これが彼らのランディングページだ｡
And then we'll use our website helper class here to read in that URL and get the contents.
そして､ このウェブサイト・ヘルパークラスを使ってURLを読み込み､ 内容を取得する｡
So this is all making sense.
だから､ これはすべて理にかなっている｡
We're just going to to get the contents of the website.
ウェブサイトのコンテンツを取得するだけだ｡
We're going to turn that into a prompt.
それをプロンプトに変えるんだ｡
And then if it's GPT we're going to stream from GPT.
そしてGPTならGPTからストリーミングする｡
If it's Claude, we're going to stream from Claude.
クロードなら､ クロードからストリーミングするつもりだ｡
Um, otherwise we'll raise an error and we will then make this a generator and yield the results chunk
ええと､ そうでなければエラーを発生させ､ これをジェネレーターにして､ チャンクごとに結果を出します｡
Uh, I realize it's a bit bit misleading to call this chunk because it's in fact not actually chunk
このチャンクをチャンクと呼ぶのは少し誤解を招くかもしれない｡
It's it's the full amount.
全額だ｡
So you might want to rename that something that's, uh, a better reflection of what this this is.
だから､ この名前を変更した方がいいかもしれない｡
But you get the idea.
でも､ おわかりだろう｡
It should do the trick.
それでうまくいくはずだ｡
Uh, so wouldn't it be nice?
ええと､ それならいいんじゃない？
I'm going to stop saying that because it's going to get old.
もう古くなるから言うのはやめるよ｡
But it is nice.
でも､ いいものだよ｡
It is as simple as now just replacing the function with stream brochure.
これはもう､ 関数をストリームパンフレットに置き換えるだけの簡単なことだ｡
And you can see here the inputs.
そして､ ここにインプットを見ることができる｡
We of course have these three inputs.
もちろん､ この3つのインプットはある｡
Now we have a company name.
これで社名が決まった｡
We have a landing page URL.
ランディングページのURLがあります｡
And then we can pick the model.
そしてモデルを選ぶことができる｡
And let's give that a whirl.
そして､ それを試してみよう｡
Uh here we go.
さあ､ 行くぞ｡
Running locally.
ローカルで走っている｡
Bring it up so we can say company name hugging face.
社名を抱きしめている顔を言えるように､ その話を持ち出そう｡
Landing page URL we can say.
ランディングページのURL
And we'll just do a.
そして､ ただやるだけだ｡
Hugging s.co and select model.
Sを抱きしめる｡  コとモデルを選択する｡
We will ask GPT to be first add it and then just press submit.
まずGPTに追加を依頼し､ 送信を押すだけだ｡
And here it goes.
そして､ こうなる｡
Here is our company brochure for Huggingface streaming back in markdown based on our web scrape.
Huggingfaceの会社案内を､ ウェブスクレイプに基づきマークダウンしてお届けします｡
It's all there.
すべてそこにある｡
It's even got links down at the bottom for different things.
下の方にいろいろなリンクがある｡
Uh, and yeah, that link looks like that is correct.
ああ､ そのリンクは正しいようだ｡
That's going to work.
うまくいきそうだ｡
Some of these links look like they're not going to work because of, uh, how it's been generated.
これらのリンクのいくつかは､ その､ 生成された方法のために機能しないように見える｡
But still, that's a pretty impressive web page, I've got to say, an impressive brochure.
それにしても､ かなり印象的なウェブページ､ 印象的なパンフレットと言わざるを得ない｡
I mean, I love it.
つまり､ 大好きなんだ｡
Let's see what Claude does with this Claude haiku.
クロードがこのクロード俳句で何をするか見てみよう｡
Of course.
もちろんだ｡
So it's, uh, a slimmer model, but it's perfectly acceptable.
だから､ スリムなモデルだが､ まったく問題ない｡
Let's build the future of AI together.
AIの未来を一緒に築いていきましょう｡
Uh, very nice brochure there from haiku.
ええと､ 俳句のパンフレットはとても良かったよ｡
Uh, and there we go.
ああ､ そうだ｡
I'm.
私は｡
I'm blown away every time I use gradio by how simple it is, how effective it is.
gradioを使うたびに､ そのシンプルさと効果に驚かされる｡
We've just built a user interface around our brochure where you can pick between different models and
私たちはパンフレットを中心に､ さまざまなモデルを選べるユーザー・インターフェイスを構築しました｡
So the to dos for you, the ways you can make this better are there are so many.
だから､ あなたにとってやるべきこと､ これをより良くする方法はたくさんある｡
You could, as I say, add Gemini not only to the earlier example, but to this one as well.
先ほどの例だけでなく､ この例にも双子座を加えることができる｡
Another idea is you could add in another selection, another drop down where you can pick the the style,
もう一つのアイデアは､ 別の選択項目を追加して､ 前回覚えているスタイルや口調を選択できるようにすることだ｡
Well, why don't you set it so you can pick from that drop down, choose a different tone, and then
それなら､ ドロップダウンから別のトーンを選んで､ そのトーンで会社案内を作成できるように設定したらどうだろう｡
Uh, it's actually super easy to do that.
それはとても簡単なことなんだ｡
So give it a try.
だから試してみてほしい｡
Do that.
そうしてくれ｡
And you'll have really beefed up this application to be something that that is increasingly high in
そして､ このアプリケーションをますます機能性の高いものに強化していくのだ｡
So I hope you have fun doing that.
だから､ それを楽しんでほしい｡
Check in the code afterwards.
その後､ コードを確認する｡
So I get to see it.
だから私はそれを見ることができる｡
And I will see you in the next lecture for the wrap up.
それではまた､ 次回の講義でお会いしましょう｡